Understand, Kobato!?
Summer vacation is our rival!
Rival?
That's right!
Summer vacation is all about going to the sea, catching bugs, splitting watermelons!
It's full of ways to draw people's attention away from the scars and pain within their hearts!
Hey, Dobato, are you even listening!?
A letter...
That's not a letter, that's a flyer!
I told you you wouldn't get anywhere with collecting candy like this!
Even more importantly, summer festivals are a serious foe.
Flutes and taiko, festivals and yukata, the list just goes on and on.
It's pretty.
Listen up, Kobato!
Don't you even understand what I'm saying!?
I'm not done talking yet!
I won't lose to summer vacation! I'll heal everyone's scarred hearts!
What shall I do?
Even the obvious things are always so hard
I just want to grin when I'm happy, sing when I'm in love
They say my dreams will come true someday
but when will someday come? I can't wait!
Count one, two, three and spread my arms
Gather the light to myself
Where is it? Tell me what I can do
Even if I'm hurt so much, even if I run so hard
Even if I collapse crying over and over, I still
believe in my amazing future
... Summer memories.
A summer festival...
Where did it fly off to?
This?
Yes, that's it!
Thank you.
Hold on a second.
Use this.
Your hands are all wet.
Thank you!
What's she up to?
It's a flyer for the summer festival!
That's right, it's about time for that.
Have you ever gone?
Every year since I was a little girl.
The portable shrine, the festival, the fireworks...
Fireworks...?
But I'm not going this year.
Why?
Let's race when we get to the pool!
Fine! I won't lose!
Oh yeah? I learned to swim!
Really?
That's great!
I've got to get going.
I have classes today.
Yomogi Nursery has the summer off!
Ow...
Yukino...
Good morning, Nacchan!
You were looking at your phone rather than where you were walking again, huh.
If you don't hurry up, you'll be late.
Are you okay?
Kobato...
Ioryogi!
I'm so heavy...
Are you okay?
No way!
I've been telling you, we can't let summer vacation beat us!
Hold still!
I'm gonna get you fired up!
Dry me out.
Hm, that uniform's from Seinan Girls' Academy.
Do you know Nacchan, Fujimoto?
Nope.
It's a high school attached to a womens' college.
Sayaka and Chitose graduated from there.
You know so much...
It's a school for young ladies. It's completely out of your league.
He's being mean again.
Isn't he busy with work and studying while the nursery's out?
Anyway, I'm dry.
Are you going to go give this back?
That's right!
Nacchan isn't here.
If you don't hurry up, it's gonna get dark.
block
At the beginning of the second semester,
Oh, there she is!
block
Mizuhashi Natsuki accepted a commendation from the prefectural govenment for green-up efforts
on behalf of the Volunteer Club.
So Nacchan is named Mizuhashi Natsuki.
I wonder if she's in the same class as the airhead.
block
Don't stay up late just because it's vacation!
Oh, it's the girl from this morning.
block
It's easy to slack off during summer vacation.
Students of Seinan should show proper moderation...
You again, Morikawa?
If you don't cool it, I'm taking that thing!
So-Sorry...
block
Anyway, let's go over our emergency contacts for summer vacation.
Wow, that's a great shot!
You have a good sense for it.
Really?
Have some self-confidence.
block
That is all.
Would those responsible for pool cleaning please gather at poolside.
Here they come!
Okay!
Excuse me!
Are you a student here?
No, I'm Hanato Kobato from Yomogi Nursery.
Nursery? What are you talking about!?
You over there! Hurry up and get someone from the office.
This sucks. Run away, Kobato!
Why?
Just do it!
Okay, I'll try!
Hey! Hold it!
Anyway, I've got to find Natsuki.
Hold it by the lens.
The real thing is great!
Aren't you going to buy one soon, Yukinocchi?
That's the girl that was with Nacchan this morning.
You're Yukino, right?
I'm Hanato Kobato!
Nacchan!
She was looking for you.
You're the girl from this morning.
I'm Hanato Kobato!
I'm returning your handkerchief!
You washed it?
Yes! But I don't have an iron, so it's all wrinkled.
Don't worry about that. Thank you.
All right, I'm out of here.
What about the pool cleaning?
Sorry. I didn't tell you, but I have work...
Isn't that against the school rules?
I know, but...
Yukino!
We're late!
Sorry, Nacchan.
Yukino...
She's trying her hardest to buy a camera.
We're helping with the pool, so you can go ahead today!
I didn't know...
Natsuki!
I'll come along with you!
It's just like Fujimoto said.
It is out of my league.
Just saying "I'll come along with you!" out of nowhere is a pretty lame pickup line.
Pickup?
That's lame?
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Sorry to try and pick you up!
I didn't want to go home alone either, so it cheered me up.
That's nice.
This photo...
It looks like Yukino.
It's from a summer festival when we were in grade school.
You look so happy together!
Happy together, huh?
Don't you get along now?
Well, she's been avoiding me...
'Morning, Nacchan.
Good morning, Yukino.
Your shirt's untucked in back.
I'll get it for you.
We always used to walk to school together.
Sorry I'm late.
Your bed head's horrible, Yukino!
No way! Hold on!
Hurry up, Yukino!
But then it started.
Sorry, Nacchan, I overslept! Go ahead without me!
Sure, okay.
It got worse when we started high school...
See you.
So pretty...
Sorry, Nacchan, you can go ahead.
Yukino, if you're in to photography, you should join the club!
I'm not sure I'm that into it...
Come on, just come and watch one day!
No way...
Come on!
Lately, we've been completely seperated.
What is she thinking?
I don't know...
I want to help Natsuki!
How?
I don't know!
What do you mean "I don't understand"!?
Anyway, I'm going to try talking with Yukino.
Good work.
That should be enough for the festival.
Yeah.
Take whichever you like.
Sorry to bother you at work.
Nah, don't worry, I'm already done.
Really?
I've finally got the money together. Tomorrow I'll be able to go to the mall by the train station and buy a camera!
Different from the one you had yesterday?
Yesterday?
That was a friend's.
I want my own so badly. That's why I got a job.
That's amazing, Yukino.
I got interested using my phone's camera,
but now I'm really into it!
I love my new friends in the photography club, too.
We talk so much!
How about Natsuki?
Don't you talk with Natsuki?
They match!
Yeah.
Let's go buy straps!
Matching ones!
I dunno about matching even that...
Really...
I'll get this one!
Then I'll get this.
Natsuki, so watermelon.
Yukino, so a snowman.
They're cute!
Shall we swap?
Yeah.
I'll take good care of it.
Me too.
Don't you get along with her any more?
Do you hate her now?
No, there's no way I'd hate her!
I look up to her so much...
Oh man, that's embarassing.
Let's take one together.
Yeah.
Cheese!
Let me take the next one!
When you get better at it!
Natsuki and Yukino both want to get along better, so why can't they?
Dunno. If they can't figure it out, why do you think you can?
But I want to do something.
Excuse me, which camera shop is having the sale?
It's that one.
Thanks.
Let's try it out when we get back.
That'll be great.
Nacchan...
You went shopping?
Yeah.
A single-lens reflex camera...
You worked hard and got a good camera.
Yeah, we're jealous even though we're in the photography club!
Yukinocchi, you should join!
Yeah, it'd be great!
To remember your SLR debut...
You finally bought the camera you wanted.
Yeah! You should come to the next shoot!
You're talented, I'm sure you'll take great photos!
Stupid!
There's lots of people who mistakenly think just composing a shot like you see in ads makes you a good photographer.
Aren't you one of them, Yukino?
Amateurs who act all pro even though they don't have any talent are the worst.
Yukino!
Natsuki!
Yukino?
Well, I'd like to have talent,
but for now I just enjoy taking pictures and like cameras.
Well... Um...
I'm glad you bought the camera you wanted. Now...
Sorry.
Can you leave me alone for a while?
Why did I say that!?
It's gone! The strap is gone!
Why?
It's gone!
Hey, where are you going now?
That isn't like Natsuki.
I have to tell her something!
Tell her what?
Well...
Anyway, we can't just leave her like this!
What happened?
It's gone! The strap is gone!
I'll help!
I looked there over and over. It's gone!
What can I do...
I was so mean to Yukino...
That's why it's gone!
Anyway, I'll help look!
What do I do... I... I...
Natsuki...
There it is!
Thank you...
Thank you, Kobato.
So you two really can still get along.
I think I was afraid of Yukino...
Because of how wonderfully serious she was?
Yukino had changed a bit from back then,
and now and then it felt like she was getting distant.
I was really worried that she was brushing me aside.
So I didn't know what to do except focus on studying and stuff.
In the end, I pushed her away first.
Natsuki, can I borrow your phone?
Nacchan...
I'm sorry.
Nacchan still has it...
Yukino...
Yukino, I said such horrible things...
Um...
Me too.
I still have mine too.
Yukino...
Miss Sayaka, Chihiro, have you two ever fought?
I can't even remember how many times.
Really?
Sometimes we wouldn't even speak afterwards.
Yeah, that definitely happened.
But you still get along.
Nacchan, smile!
It's embarassing!
The fireworks are pretty.
90 points for today.
Take that, you thief!
The fireworks are so pretty!
What are you doing getting healed by the summer festival!?
That's it. Minus 200 points, Dobato!
Aren't the fireworks so pretty?
Hey, listen to people when they talk to you!
They're pretty...
People all want to fly
but they're cheated by gravity
everyone can really fly
She must be so unhappy because
she forgot her own shadow somewhere
Then...
If you tell me "thanks", if you say "thanks" and smile
Going back and forth, we'll be happy
You'll be happy, there'll be nothing to worry about
As long as we're together
It's strange, I'm crying even though I'm happy
... An organ, and boyhood days.
Next episode